Guide to the Student Life at Yale Photographs
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Student life at Yale photographs
1774-1988
RU 736
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
19.5
The materials consist of photographs and drawings documenting various aspects of student life and activities at Yale. Included are pictures of commencement ceremonies, class day activities, parties and dances, sports, protests, theatrical performances, classroom and other interior scenes, and Yale during wartime.
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 41 (YRG 41), Material documenting Yale student life.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
The materials consist of photographs and drawings documenting various aspects of student life and activities at Yale. Included are pictures of commencement ceremonies, class day activities, parties and dances, sports, protests, theatrical performances, classroom and other interior scenes, and Yale during wartime.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged in four series and in subsequent accessions. I. Photographs and pictures of student life, Yale University, circa 1779-1988. II. Oversize. III. Folio. IV. Slides.
The photographs are arranged alphabetically by subject.
Student activities; Drawings (visual works); Photographs; Yale College (1718-1887) -- Students; Yale University -- Sports; Yale University -- Students
- Photographs and pictures of student life, Yale University, circa 1779-1988; Series I
  General note
  see also: RU 690 Photographs of events and activities
  Scope and Contents
  Photographs are listed alphabetically by subject, thereunder chronologically. Patrons should also refer to the OVERSIZE, FOLIO, and subseqent accession lists at the end of the finding aid. For pictorial materials relating to clubs and societies, refer to YRG 40; for materials relating to collegiate athletics, refer to YRG 38.
  - Assemblies
    - 1944 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Informal talks, 1960s (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Unidentified lecture, 1930s (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Unidentified, Undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Baccalaureate
    - 1938 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - 1939 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - 1967 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Bladderball
    - 1962 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - 1966 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Burial of Euclid (engravings) (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Bursary jobs
    - 1937 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - 1938 (Box 1, Folder 13-14)
    - Horace Walpole Collection, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 14A)
  - Calcium Light Night
    - 1864 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - 1892 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - 1904 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - 1907 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - 1907 or 1908 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - 1908 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - 1910 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - 1911-1913 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Circa 1930-1940 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - 1933 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - 1937 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - 1939 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - 1940 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - "Campus Characters"
    - Candy Sam, Circa 1860-1875 (Box 1, Folder 28-30)
    - Ajax the newsboy, 1863 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - "Leviathan", Circa 1870-1890? (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Hannibal (candy seller), Circa 1875 (Box 1, Folder 33-34)
    - "Old Mountain Phelps", 1876 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - David Breckinridge (candy man), 1880 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Frank E. Hotchkiss ("King Whichkiss")- cartoon from Yale Banner, Circa 1880 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Mailmen, Circa 1884-1885 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - "Shorty Moses"-College old clothes man, Circa 1890 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - "Pop" Smith, Circa 1809-1905 (Box 1, Folder 40-41)
    - "Pop" Warner, 1904 (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - Leo Morris, 1904 (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - God Bless You Mary, Circa 1914 (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - Cornelius the Laundry Man, 1929 (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - Jerry the Newsboy, Circa 1930-1962 (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - "Rosie" the old clothes man, 1936-circa 1947 (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - Amato the shoe man, 1937 (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - Peanut vendor, Undated (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - Daniel Pratt (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - Unidentified (Box 2, Folder 51-52)
  - Cartoons and Drawings
    - George Welles, captain of Student's Co., by St. John Honeywood, Circa 1779 (Box 2, Folder 53)
    - Pencil drawings -- possibly by J. A. Hillhouse, Circa 1800-1810 (Box 2, Folder 54)
    - Miscellaneous Yale cartoons, 1836 (Box 2, Folder 55)
    - Theodore Hittel's pen and ink sketches (Box 2, Folder 56-57)
    - Exams -- Biennial, Circa 1850 (Box 2, Folder 58)
    - Ballou's Monthly -- four engravings, 1856-1857 (Box 2, Folder 59)
    - "Amusement of students at Yale" -- etching, 1861 (Box 2, Folder 60)
    - "The Unsolved Problem" -- coeducation, 1872 (Box 2, Folder 61)
    - The Great Russian Conflict -- Battle of Shitzka, 1877 (Box 2, Folder 62)
    - Furniture sale -- from Yale Banner, 1883-1884 (Box 2, Folder 63)
    - J. D. Dewell and Co. -- engraving, 1889 (Box 2, Folder 64)
    - Football spectators, Circa 1890 (Box 2, Folder 65)
    - Yale Banner centerfold re: coeducation, 1893 (Box 2, Folder 66)
    - Football victory fire -- by F.V. Sikes, 1900 (Box 2, Folder 67)
    - H. Christian cartoons, 1901 (Box 2, Folder 68)
    - Racoon coat, 1924 (Box 2, Folder 69)
    - "Life in Frosty Farnum" (Box 2, Folder 70)
    - Football cartoons by Carl Bates, Y 1942, Circa 1942 (Box 2, Folder 71)
    - Original cartoon by Lawrence Larian, 1944 (Box 2, Folder 72)
    - Cartoons by R. Grossman, Circa 1961 (Box 2, Folder 73)
  - Chapel scenes (Box 2, Folder 73)
  - From Kingsley's History, 1879 (circa 1824)
    - 1907, 1910, 1911 (Box 2, Folder 75)
    - Easter outside Battell, 1936? (Box 2, Folder 76)
    - Exterior, 1937 (Box 2, Folder 77)
  - Class Day
    - Planting the ivy
      - 1876 (Box 2, Folder 78)
      - Circa 1880-1890 (Box 2, Folder 79)
      - 1885 (Box 2, Folder 80)
      - 1887 (Box 2, Folder 81)
      - Circa 1880-1900 (Box 2, Folder 82)
    - Class histories
      - 1892 (Box 3, Folder 83)
      - 1897 (Box 3, Folder 84)
      - 1903 (Box 3, Folder 85)
      - 1905 (Box 3, Folder 86)
      - Circa 1910 (Box 3, Folder 87)
    - Speakers
      - 1910 (Box 3, Folder 88)
      - 1915 (Box 3, Folder 89)
      - Circa 1920-1929 (Box 3, Folder 90)
      - 1929 (Box 3, Folder 91)
      - Circa 1930-1935 (Box 3, Folder 92)
      - Circa 1930-1933 (Box 3, Folder 93)
      - 1931 (Box 3, Folder 94)
      - 1932 (Box 3, Folder 95)
      - 1933 (Box 3, Folder 96)
      - 1934 (Box 3, Folder 97-98)
    - Speakers-Sheffield
      - 1934 (Box 3, Folder 99)
      - 1935 (Box 3, Folder 100)
      - 1936 (Box 3, Folder 101)
      - 1937 (Box 3, Folder 102)
      - 1938 (Box 3, Folder 103-106)
      - 1939 (Box 3, Folder 107-108)
      - 1940 (Box 3, Folder 109)
      - 1941 (Box 3, Folder 110)
      - Circa 1941-1945 (Box 3, Folder 111)
      - 1942 (Box 3, Folder 112)
      - 1943 (Box 3, Folder 113)
      - 1944 (Box 3, Folder 114)
      - 1947 (Box 3, Folder 115)
      - Photo of program, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 116)
      - 1960 (Box 3, Folder 117)
      - Officers, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 118)
      - 1967 (Box 3, Folder 119)
      - 1969 (Box 3, Folder 120)
  - Class Deacons, Circa 1912 (Box 3, Folder 121)
  - Classroom scenes
    - Outside, leaving class, 1920s (Box 3, Folder 122)
    - Outside, leaving class, 1930s (Box 3, Folder 123)
    - 1937-1938 (Box 3, Folder 124-125)
    - Richard A. Rathbone of Art School, 1939 (Box 3, Folder 126)
    - English class under Stanley T. Williams (Box 3, Folder 127)
    - Unidentified, 1950s (Box 4, Folder 128)
    - Faculty-student conference, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 129)
    - Panel discussion -- Calhoun College, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 130)
    - Lecture, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 131)
    - Undated (Box 4, Folder 132)
  - Commencement
    - Circa 1890-1900 (Box 4, Folder 133)
    - Circa 1900 (Box 4, Folder 134-135)
    - Circa 1900-1910 (Box 4, Folder 136)
    - Circa 1900-1920 (Box 4, Folder 137)
    - with William Howard Taft and J.P. Morgan, 1908 (Box 4, Folder 138-139)
    - 1910 (Box 4, Folder 140)
    - with Omega Lambda Chi, 1911 (Box 4, Folder 141)
    - 1914 (Box 4, Folder 142)
    - 1915 (Box 4, Folder 143)
    - with Herbert Hoover, 1918 (Box 4, Folder 144)
    - 1919 (Box 4, Folder 145)
    - Circa 1921 (Box 4, Folder 146)
    - Circa 1921-1937 (Box 4, Folder 147)
    - 1924 (Box 4, Folder 148)
    - 1926 (Box 4, Folder 149)
    - 1927 (Box 4, Folder 150)
    - 1928 (Box 4, Folder 151-152)
    - 1929 (Box 4, Folder 153)
    - 1930 (Box 4, Folder 154)
    - Circa 1930-1940 (Box 4, Folder 155)
    - Honorary Degree recipients
      - 1931 (Box 4, Folder 156)
      - 1932 (Box 4, Folder 157-158)
      - 1933 (Box 4, Folder 159)
      - with Franklin D. Roosevelt, 1934 (Box 4, Folder 160-161)
      - 1935 (Box 4, Folder 162-163)
      - 1936 (Box 4, Folder 164-166)
      - 1937 (Box 4, Folder 167-168)
      - 1937 (Box 5, Folder 169)
      - 1937-1950 (Box 5, Folder 170)
      - with Walt Disney, 1938 (Box 5, Folder 171-172)
      - 1939 (Box 5, Folder 173-176)
      - 1940 (Box 5, Folder 177-178)
      - 1941 (Box 5, Folder 179-180)
      - 1942 (Box 5, Folder 181-183)
    - Planting the ivy, 1945 (Box 5, Folder 184)
    - with Dwight D. Eisenhower, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 185)
    - 1950 (Box 5, Folder 186)
    - Circa 1950-1960 (Box 5, Folder 187)
    - Circa 1950-1963 (Box 5, Folder 188)
    - 1951 (Box 5, Folder 189)
    - 1952 (Box 5, Folder 190)
    - 1953 (Box 5, Folder 191)
    - 1954 (Box 5, Folder 192)
    - Pierson College, 1955 (Box 5, Folder 193)
    - 1958 (Box 5, Folder 194)
    - 1950 (Box 5, Folder 195)
    - 1960 (Box 5, Folder 196)
    - with John F. Kennedy, 1962 (Box 5, Folder 197)
    - 1961 (Box 5, Folder 196A)
    - 1963 (Box 5, Folder 198)
    - 1965 (Box 5, Folder 199)
    - 1966 (Box 5, Folder 200-201)
    - 1966 (Box 6, Folder 202-203)
    - with Duke Ellington, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 204-205)
    - 1968 (Box 6, Folder 206-207)
    - 1969 (Box 6, Folder 208-209)
    - 1971 (Box 6, Folder 210-213)
    - 1973 (Box 6, Folder 214)
    - with Ella Fitzgerald, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 215)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 6, Folder 216)
  - Committees
    - Class Book -- Sheffield, Circa 1916 (Box 6, Folder 217)
    - Class Book
      - 1931 (Box 6, Folder 218)
      - 1932 (Box 6, Folder 219)
      - 1935 (Box 6, Folder 220)
      - 1962 (Box 6, Folder 221)
    - Class Day
      - 1930 (Box 6, Folder 222)
      - 1931 (Box 6, Folder 223)
      - 1932 (Box 6, Folder 224)
      - 1934 (Box 6, Folder 225)
      - 1935 (Box 6, Folder 226)
    - Freshman Council
      - 1931 (Box 6, Folder 227)
      - 1932 (Box 6, Folder 228)
      - 1933 (Box 6, Folder 229)
      - 1934 (Box 6, Folder 230)
    - Freshman Discipline
      - 1931 (Box 6, Folder 231)
      - 1932 (Box 7, Folder 232)
    - Freshman Yearbook Board
      - 1931 (Box 7, Folder 233)
      - 1932 (Box 7, Folder 234)
      - 1932-1933 (Box 7, Folder 235)
    - Freshman Activities, Class of, 1962 (Box 7, Folder 236)
    - Freshman Prom, 1934 (Box 7, Folder 237)
    - Junior Prom
      - 1893 (Box 7, Folder 238)
      - 1895 (Box 7, Folder 239)
      - 1899 (Box 7, Folder 240)
      - 1902 (Box 7, Folder 241)
      - 1916 (Box 7, Folder 242)
      - 1931 (Box 7, Folder 243)
      - 1932 (Box 7, Folder 244)
      - 1933 (Box 7, Folder 245)
      - 1934 (Box 7, Folder 246)
      - 1962 (Box 7, Folder 247)
      - 1974 (Box 7, Folder 248)
    - Senior Prom
      - Circa 1930s (Box 7, Folder 249)
      - 1931 (Box 7, Folder 250)
      - 1934 (Box 7, Folder 251)
      - 1948 (Box 7, Folder 252)
    - Sophomore Committee, Undated (Box 7, Folder 253)
    - Thanksgiving Jubilee, 1865 (Box 7, Folder 254)
    - Thanksgiving Jubilee, Circa 1869 (Box 7, Folder 255)
    - Triennial, 1931 (Box 7, Folder 256)
    - Triennial, 1932 (Box 7, Folder 257)
  - County Jail fire, 1910 February (Box 7, Folder 258)
  - Courtyard scenes
    - 1880s (Box 7, Folder 259)
    - Photos by Norton, Circa 1890-1900 (Box 7, Folder 260)
    - (Branford?), 1920s (Box 7, Folder 261)
    - Circa 1930s (Box 7, Folder 262)
    - 1937 (Box 7, Folder 263)
    - 1939 (Box 7, Folder 264)
    - 1940 (Box 7, Folder 265)
    - Branford, 1943 (Box 7, Folder 266)
    - Daffodils-by G. H. Hamilton, Jr., Y. 1949, Circa 1949 (Box 7, Folder 267)
    - 1950s (Box 7, Folder 268)
  - Dances and Parties
    - Junior Prom
      - 1892 (Box 7, Folder 269)
      - [1894?] (Box 7, Folder 270)
      - 1895 (Box 7, Folder 271)
      - Circa 1896 (Box 7, Folder 272)
      - 1899 (Box 7, Folder 273)
      - 1900 (Box 7, Folder 274)
      - 1902 (Box 8, Folder 275)
      - 1903 (Box 8, Folder 276)
      - 1904 (Box 8, Folder 277)
      - 1905 (Box 8, Folder 278)
      - 1906 (Box 8, Folder 279)
      - Class of 1909S and 1910, 1908-1909 (Box 8, Folder 280)
      - 1918 (Box 8, Folder 281)
      - 1924 (Box 8, Folder 281)
      - 1935 (Box 8, Folder 282)
      - 1937 (Box 8, Folder 283)
      - 1938 (Box 8, Folder 284-285)
      - 1962 (Box 8, Folder 286)
    - Senior Prom, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 287)
    - Unidentified Prom, Circa 1930s (Box 8, Folder 288)
    - Unidentified Prom, Circa 1940s (Box 8, Folder 289)
    - German Dance, 1902 (Box 8, Folder 290)
    - Association with Yale men, Circa 1910 (Box 8, Folder 291)
    - House party, Circa 1910 (Box 8, Folder 292)
    - Derby Day, 1923 (Box 8, Folder 293)
    - Derby Day, 1947 (Box 8, Folder 294)
    - Christmas parties, 1937 (Box 8, Folder 295)
    - Fraternity party, 1937 (Box 8, Folder 296)
    - Branford College dinner, 1942 (Box 8, Folder 297)
    - Branford College beer party, 1943 (Box 8, Folder 298)
    - Berkeley College, 1962 (Box 8, Folder 299)
    - Calhoun College Christmas party, 1962 (Box 8, Folder 300)
    - Timothy Dwight College, 1962 (Box 8, Folder 301)
    - Freshman Dance, 1962 (Box 8, Folder 302)
    - Jonathan Edwards College, "Roman Orgy", 1962 (Box 8, Folder 303)
    - Jonathan Edwards College, "Spook Night", 1962 (Box 8, Folder 304)
    - "The Twist", 1962 (Box 8, Folder 305-310)
    - Unidentified (Box 8, Folder 305-310)
    - 1900-1910 (Box 9, Folder 311)
    - 1930s (Box 9, Folder 312)
    - 1940s (Box 9, Folder 313)
    - 1956 (Box 9, Folder 314)
    - 1960s (Box 9, Folder 315)
    - Undated (Box 9, Folder 316)
  - Dining Hall scenes
    - Berkeley College, 1969 (Box 9, Folder 317)
    - Branford College, 1962 (Box 9, Folder 318)
    - Branford College, 1972 (Box 9, Folder 319)
    - Commons, Circa 1950s (Box 9, Folder 320)
    - Davenport College, 1930s (Box 9, Folder 321)
    - Davenport College, 1962 (Box 9, Folder 322)
    - Pierson College, 1940 (Box 9, Folder 323)
    - Saybrook College, formal dinner, 1962 (Box 9, Folder 324)
    - Trumbull College, 1962 (Box 9, Folder 325)
    - 1938 (Box 9, Folder 326)
    - 1950s (Box 9, Folder 327)
    - Unidentified, Undated (Box 9, Folder 328)
  - East Rock, cleaning of defacement, Circa 1935 (Box 9, Folder 329)
  - Eating Club -- unidentified, 1867 (Box 9, Folder 330)
  - Examinations, Circa 1850s (Box 9, Folder 331)
  - Examinations, outside Alumni Hall, 1900-1920 (Box 9, Folder 332)
  - Foreign Students
    - Chinese students at Yale, Circa 1907-1923 (Box 9, Folder 333)
    - Unidentified, 1950s (Box 9, Folder 334)
    - Foreign students and scholars, Undated (Box 9, Folder 335)
  - Freshman Activities
    - Picture assembly, Circa 1900-1910 (Box 9, Folder 336)
    - Rally, 1935 (Box 9, Folder 337)
    - Freshman prize winners, [1936?] (Box 9, Folder 338)
    - Registration, 1937 (Box 9, Folder 339)
    - Registration, 1938 (Box 9, Folder 340)
    - Freshman Counseling Committee, 1938 (Box 9, Folder 341)
    - General, 1938 (Box 9, Folder 342)
    - Rallies and parties, 1940 (Box 9, Folder 343)
    - Freshman Counselor, 1941 (Box 9, Folder 344)
    - Rallies, 1941-1942 (Box 9, Folder 345)
    - Registration, 1962 (Box 9, Folder 346)
    - Christmas Dinner at Commons, 1939 (Box 9, Folder 347)
    - Reception -- President Seymour, 1939 (Box 9, Folder 348)
    - Tea at President Seymour's house, 1944 (Box 9, Folder 349)
    - Freshman picnic at Hammonassett, 1948 (Box 9, Folder 350)
    - Freshman Week, 1954 (Box 9, Folder 351)
    - Wright Hall residents, 1922 (Box 10, Folder 352)
  - Groups -- miscellaneous and unidentified
    - Late 19th century (Box 10, Folder 353-354)
    - Late 20th century (Box 10, Folder 355)
    - 1920s (Box 10, Folder 356)
    - 1930s (Box 10, Folder 357)
    - 1940s (Box 10, Folder 358)
    - 1950s (Box 10, Folder 359)
  - Handsome Dan (Box 10, Folder 360-361)
  - Health Services, serving patients, 1938, 1942 (Box 10, Folder 362)
  - Individuals -- unidentified students on campus (Box 10, Folder 363)
  - Leisure time activities
    - Beer and bike race -- Trumbull College, 1953-1962 (Box 10, Folder 364)
    - Bicycling, 1934 (Box 10, Folder 365)
    - Bobsledders, Circa 1930s (Box 10, Folder 366)
    - Butteries, 1962 (Box 10, Folder 367)
    - "Charming" cobra -- Pierson College, 1962 (Box 10, Folder 368)
    - Circus, 1914 (Box 10, Folder 369)
    - Drinking at Mory's, 1937 (Box 10, Folder 370)
    - Games
      - Marbles, 1893 (Box 10, Folder 371)
      - Spinning Tops, Circa 1907 (Box 10, Folder 372)
      - Rolling hoops, Circa 1907 (Box 10, Folder 373)
      - "Nigger baby", 1886 (Box 10, Folder 374)
      - Leapfrog, 1910, 1943 (Box 10, Folder 375)
      - Pyramid "Horsing", 1910 (Box 10, Folder 376)
    - Baseball
      - 1910-1916 (Box 10, Folder 377)
      - 1930s-1940s (Box 10, Folder 378)
      - 1956 (Box 10, Folder 379)
    - Canoeing, Undated (Box 10, Folder 379A)
    - Cards
      - 1890s (Box 10, Folder 380)
      - 1950s (Box 10, Folder 381)
      - Undated (Box 10, Folder 382)
    - Checkers on Old Campus, 1937 (Box 10, Folder 383)
    - Football, 1940s (Box 11, Folder 384)
    - Football, 1960s (Box 11, Folder 385)
    - Juggling, Circa 1970s (Box 11, Folder 385)
    - Ping-pong, 1962 (Box 11, Folder 386)
    - [Pitching pennies?], 1940s (Box 11, Folder 387)
    - Pool, 1950s (Box 11, Folder 388)
    - Pool, 1962 (Box 11, Folder 389)
    - Solitaire, 1962 (Box 11, Folder 390)
    - Tennis, Undated (Box 11, Folder 391)
    - Going abroad on "Bremen", 1926 (Box 11, Folder 392)
    - on the New Haven Green, 1965 (Box 11, Folder 393)
    - Ice skating, 1960s (Box 11, Folder 394)
    - In costume, Undated (Box 11, Folder 394A)
    - Laundry, 1956 (Box 11, Folder 395)
    - Movies, 1938 (Box 11, Folder 396)
    - Music, 1956 (Box 11, Folder 397)
    - Music, 1962-1965 (Box 11, Folder 398)
    - Picnics, 1962 (Box 11, Folder 399)
    - Reading a newspaper, Circa 1950s (Box 11, Folder 399A)
    - Roller skating, Circa 1890-1900 (Box 11, Folder 400)
    - Shopping, 1938 (Box 11, Folder 401)
    - Swimming, 1940 (Box 11, Folder 402)
    - Taking train for ski trip, 1936 (Box 11, Folder 403)
    - Walking, Undated (Box 11, Folder 403A)
    - Yachting, 1895 (Box 11, Folder 404)
  - Library scenes
    - Photos by Aikens, 1934 (Box 11, Folder 405)
    - Sterling Library -- exterior, 1938 (Box 11, Folder 406)
    - 1950s (Box 11, Folder 407)
    - Unidentified College, 1956 (Box 11, Folder 408)
    - Branford College, 1962 (Box 11, Folder 409)
    - Pierson College, 1962 (Box 11, Folder 410)
    - Silliman College, 1962 (Box 11, Folder 411)
    - Sterling library
      - Card catalogues, 1966 (Box 11, Folder 412)
      - Courtyards and archways, 1966 (Box 11, Folder 413)
      - Individuals, 1966 (Box 11, Folder 414)
      - Linonia and Brothers (L & B) Room, 1966 (Box 11, Folder 415)
      - Main Reading Room, Circa 1930s (Box 11, Folder 416)
  - May Day, 1970 (Box 11, Folder 417)
    General
    See also: RU 690 Photographs of events and activities
  - Medical School -- research, circa 1970s (Box 11, Folder 417)
  - Moving Day
    - Furniture sale signs
      - 1883 (Box 11, Folder 418)
      - 1892 (Box 11, Folder 419)
      - Circa 1900 (Box 11, Folder 420)
      - 1910 (Box 11, Folder 421)
    - American Express truck, 1920s (Box 11, Folder 422)
    - 1936-circa 1939 (Box 11, Folder 423)
    - early 1950s (Box 11, Folder 424)
    - 1962 (Box 11, Folder 425)
    - 1966 (Box 11, Folder 426)
  - Old Campus scenes
    - Circa 1885-1890 (Box 12, Folder 427)
    - Posters, 1887 (Box 12, Folder 428)
    - 1890s (Box 12, Folder 429-430)
    - 1900-1920 (Box 12, Folder 431)
    - Circa 1910 (Box 12, Folder 432)
    - Costumed antics, Circa 1910 (Box 12, Folder 433)
    - 1920s (Box 12, Folder 434)
    - on the Fence, Circa 1930s; Circa 1891-1895 (Box 12, Folder 435)
    - 1930s (Box 12, Folder 436)
    - 1937 (Box 12, Folder 437)
    - by Nathan Hale statue, 1938 (Box 12, Folder 438)
    - 1940s (Box 12, Folder 439)
    - 1950s, 1970s (Box 12, Folder 440)
  - Office scenes, Circa 1970s (Box 12, Folder 440A)
  - Omega Lambda Chi
    - 1910 (Box 12, Folder 441)
    - Circa 1910 (Box 12, Folder 442)
    - 1911 (Box 12, Folder 443)
    - 1915 (Box 12, Folder 444)
    - Undated (Box 12, Folder 445)
  - Yale Pageant, 1916 (Box 12, Folder 446-448)
  - Parent's Weekend -- inside and outside Commons, 1952 (Box 12, Folder 449)
  - Parent's Weekend -- at football game, 1952 (Box 12, Folder 450)
  - Peace Conference, 1938 (Box 12, Folder 451)
  - Peace Conference, 1939 (Box 12, Folder 452)
  - Plays and Shows
    - "Penikeese" cast, 1882 (Box 12, Folder 453)
    - Women dressed as men playing guitars and mandolins, Circa 1910 (Box 12, Folder 454)
    - Students in costumes, Circa 1912 (Box 12, Folder 455)
    - Spring show, 1919 (Box 12, Folder 456)
    - "Jitney Players", 1920s (Box 12, Folder 457)
    - Commons, 1936 (Box 12, Folder 458)
    - Concert in Saybrook College, 1959 July (Box 12, Folder 459)
    - Concert on Cross Campus, Circa 1960 (Box 12, Folder 460)
    - Christmas play -- Berkeley College, 1962 (Box 12, Folder 461)
    - Christmas play -- Jonathan Edwards College, 1962 (Box 12, Folder 462)
    - Indian Neck Folk Festival -- Rodger and Jamie Ness, 1962 (Box 12, Folder 463)
    - Yale Band halftime show, 1970 December (Box 12, Folder 464)
    - Unidentified college production, Undated (Box 12, Folder 465)
  - Pranks -- "The Carrie Nation Caper", 1902 (Box 12, Folder 466)
  - Presentation Day -- engraving, 1876 (Box 13, Folder 467)
  - Protests and rallies
    - Seymour Rally, 1937 (Box 13, Folder 468)
    - Jerome Davis case, 1938 (Box 13, Folder 469)
    - Princeton rally, 1948 (Box 13, Folder 470)
    - "Humpty Dumpty Riot", 1952 (Box 13, Folder 471)
    - Unidentified, 1960s (Box 13, Folder 472)
    - Bernstein affair, 1966 (Box 13, Folder 473)
    - Students for a Democratic Society, 1969-1970 (Box 13, Folder 474)
    - Buttery demonstration, Undated (Box 13, Folder 475)
  - Prizes: Putnam Memorial Prize Fund, 1928 (Box 13, Folder 476)
  - Publications
    - Banner, 1841
      - Undated (Box 13, Folder 477)
      - Board, 1931 (Box 13, Folder 477)
      - miscellaneous (Box 13, Folder 477)
    - College Courant
      - Boards, 1893-1901 (Box 13, Folder 477)
      - miscellaneous (Box 13, Folder 477)
    - Yale Daily News (Box 13, Folder 479-481)
    - Daily Zephyr, Board, 1923 (Box 13, Folder 482)
    - Literary Magazine (Box 13, Folder 483)
      - 1868 poster (Box 13, Folder 483)
      - Boards (Box 13, Folder 483)
    - Record (Boards) (Box 13, Folder 484)
    - Scientific Monthly (Box 13, Folder 485)
      - Board, 1898 (Box 13, Folder 485)
      - Banquet, 1910 (Box 13, Folder 485)
      - 1962 (Box 13, Folder 485)
  - Research
    - Students (John Lockwood, Raymond McCarthy, Philip Rice, Jr.) working on high-voltage power supply of linear accelerator, Undated (Box 13, Folder 485A)
  - Residential Colleges
    - Berkeley College, Class of, 1988 (Box 14, Folder 486)
    - Branford College, 1961-1962 (Box 14, Folder 487)
  - Rooms
    - Circa 1870s (Box 14, Folder 488)
    - Circa 1870-1890 (Box 14, Folder 489)
    - S. R. Betts -- 225 Durfee Hall, 1875 (Box 14, Folder 490)
    - Charles R. Dudley, 1877 Law (Box 14, Folder 491)